<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><dublin_core><dcvalue element="type" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Research Article</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="abstract">BackgroundSale of organic foods is one of the fastest growing market segments within the global food industry. People often buy organic food because they believe organic farms produce more nutritious and better tasting food from healthier soils. Here we tested if there are significant differences in fruit and soil quality from 13 pairs of commercial organic and conventional strawberry agroecosystems in California.Methodology/Principal FindingsAt multiple sampling times for two years, we evaluated three varieties of strawberries for mineral elements, shelf life, phytochemical composition, and organoleptic properties. We also analyzed traditional soil properties and soil DNA using microarray technology. We found that the organic farms had strawberries with longer shelf life, greater dry matter, and higher antioxidant activity and concentrations of ascorbic acid and phenolic compounds, but lower concentrations of phosphorus and potassium. In one variety, sensory panels judged organic strawberries to be sweeter and have better flavor, overall acceptance, and appearance than their conventional counterparts. We also found the organically farmed soils to have more total carbon and nitrogen, greater microbial biomass and activity, and higher concentrations of micronutrients. Organically farmed soils also exhibited greater numbers of endemic genes and greater functional gene abundance and diversity for several biogeochemical processes, such as nitrogen fixation and pesticide degradation.Conclusions/SignificanceOur findings show that the organic strawberry farms produced higher quality fruit and that their higher quality soils may have greater microbial functional capability and resilience to stress. These findings justify additional investigations aimed at detecting and quantifying such effects and their interactions.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="language" language="en_US" qualifier="iso">en_US</dcvalue><dcvalue element="title" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Fruit and Soil Quality of Organic and Conventional Strawberry Agroecosystems</dcvalue><dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2010-09-01</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">John P. Reganold</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Preston K. Andrews</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Jennifer R. Reeve</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Lynne Carpenter-Boggs</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Christopher W. Schadt</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">J. Richard Alldredge</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Carolyn F. Ross</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Neal M. Davies</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Jizhong Zhou</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="none">We thank Tom Sjulin of Driscoll's Strawberry Associates and Larry Eddings of Pacific Gold Farms for assistance with farm selection and fruit processing. We thank Linda Klein, Amit Dhingra, Patricia Ericsson, David Huggins, Jeff Smith, and two anonymous reviewers for comments on drafts of this manuscript. We thank Jan Dasgupta, Marc Evans, Gregory Peck, Sean Swezey, Carolina Torres, Canming Xiao, and Jaime Yáñez for technical assistance.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Conceived and designed the experiments: JPR PA JR LCB. Performed the experiments: JPR PA JR LCB CS CR ND. Analyzed the data: JPR PA JR LCB JRA. Contributed reagents/materials/analysis tools: JPR PA CS CR ND JZ. Wrote the paper: JPR PA JR LCB. Set up and managed the overall study: JPR.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none">PLOS ONE</dcvalue><dcvalue element="identifier" language="en_US" qualifier="citation"> Reganold JP, Andrews PK, Reeve JR, Carpenter-Boggs L, Schadt CW, et al. (2010) Fruit and Soil Quality of Organic and Conventional Strawberry Agroecosystems. PLoS ONE 5(9): e12346. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0012346</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">Attribution 3.0 United States</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="uri">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/us/</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="requestable">false</dcvalue><dcvalue element="relation" qualifier="ispartofseries">PLoS ONE 5(9):e12346</dcvalue><dcvalue element="relation" qualifier="uri">http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0012346</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">PLOS</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Public Library of Science</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Open Access</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Open-Access</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Science</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Medicine</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Biology</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Research</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Peer-review</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Inclusive</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Interdisciplinary</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Ante-disciplinary</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Physics</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Chemistry</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Engineering</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="peerreview">Yes</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="peerreviewnotes">http://www.plosone.org/static/editorial#peer</dcvalue><dcvalue element="identifier" language="en_US" qualifier="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012346</dcvalue></dublin_core>