<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><dublin_core><dcvalue element="type" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Research Article</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="abstract">Bone morphogenetic protein (BMP) retrograde signaling is crucial for neuronal development and synaptic plasticity. However, how the BMP effector phospho-Mother against decapentaplegic (pMad) is processed following receptor activation remains poorly understood. Here we show that Drosophila Epsin1/Liquid facets (Lqf) positively regulates synaptic growth through post-endocytotic processing of pMad signaling complex. Lqf and the BMP receptor Wishful thinking (Wit) interact genetically and biochemically. lqf loss of function (LOF) reduces bouton number whereas overexpression of lqf stimulates bouton growth. Lqf-stimulated synaptic overgrowth is suppressed by genetic reduction of wit. Further, synaptic pMad fails to accumulate inside the motoneuron nuclei in lqf mutants and lqf suppresses synaptic overgrowth in spinster (spin) mutants with enhanced BMP signaling by reducing accumulation of nuclear pMad. Interestingly, lqf mutations reduce nuclear pMad levels without causing an apparent blockage of axonal transport itself. Finally, overexpression of Lqf significantly increases the number of multivesicular bodies (MVBs) in the synapse whereas lqf LOF reduces MVB formation, indicating that Lqf may function in signaling endosome recycling or maturation. Based on these observations, we propose that Lqf plays a novel endosomal role to ensure efficient retrograde transport of BMP signaling endosomes into motoneuron nuclei.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="language" language="en_US" qualifier="iso">en_US</dcvalue><dcvalue element="title" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Epsin 1 Promotes Synaptic Growth by Enhancing BMP Signal Levels in Motoneuron Nuclei</dcvalue><dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2013-06-19</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Phillip A. Vanlandingham</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Taylor R. Fore</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Lerin R. Chastain</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Suzanne M. Royer</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Hong Bao</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Noreen E. Reist</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Bing Zhang</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="none">We thank Carl-Henrik Heldin (Uppsala University, Sweden) for his generous gift of the PS1 pMad antibody, Hugo Bellen, Corey Goodman, Janis Fischer, Graeme Davis, Guillermo Marques, Michael O'Connor, Kate O'Connor-Giles, and the Bloomington Drosophila Stock Center for flies strains, the Developmental Studies Hybridoma Bank at the University of Iowa for antibodies to Wit and CSP; Marie Phillips for advice on membrane fractionation; Avital Rodal, Kate O'Connor-Giles, Ela Serpe, Kristi Wharton, Mojgan Padash-Barmchi for discussions or comments on the manuscript. We also thank Jody Summers at OUHSC for her generosity in letting us to use her confocal microscope.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Conceived and designed the experiments: PAV TRF LRC BZ. Performed the experiments: PAV TRF LRC SMR HB NER BZ. Analyzed the data: PAV TRF LRC SMR HB NER BZ. Wrote the paper: PAV TRF BZ.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none">PLOS ONE</dcvalue><dcvalue element="identifier" language="en_US" qualifier="citation"> Vanlandingham PA, Fore TR, Chastain LR, Royer SM, Bao H, et al. (2013) Epsin 1 Promotes Synaptic Growth by Enhancing BMP Signal Levels in Motoneuron Nuclei. PLoS ONE 8(6): e65997. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0065997</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">Attribution 3.0 United States</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="uri">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/us/</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="requestable">false</dcvalue><dcvalue element="relation" qualifier="ispartofseries">PLoS ONE 8(6):e65997</dcvalue><dcvalue element="relation" qualifier="uri">http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0065997</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">PLOS</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Public Library of Science</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Open Access</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Open-Access</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Science</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Medicine</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Biology</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Research</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Peer-review</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Inclusive</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Interdisciplinary</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Ante-disciplinary</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Physics</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Chemistry</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Engineering</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="peerreview">Yes</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="peerreviewnotes">http://www.plosone.org/static/editorial#peer</dcvalue><dcvalue element="identifier" language="en_US" qualifier="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0065997</dcvalue></dublin_core>