<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><dublin_core><dcvalue element="type" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Research Article</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="abstract">Interest in forecasting impacts of climate change have heightened attention in recent decades to how animals respond to variation in climate and weather patterns. One difficulty in determining animal response to climate variation is lack of long-term datasets that record animal behaviors over decadal scales. We used radar observations from the national NEXRAD network of Doppler weather radars to measure how group behavior in a colonially-roosting bat species responded to annual variation in climate and daily variation in weather over the past 11 years. Brazilian free-tailed bats (Tadarida brasiliensis) form dense aggregations in cave roosts in Texas. These bats emerge from caves daily to forage at high altitudes, which makes them detectable with Doppler weather radars. Timing of emergence in bats is often viewed as an adaptive trade-off between emerging early and risking predation or increased competition and emerging late which restricts foraging opportunities. We used timing of emergence from five maternity colonies of Brazilian free-tailed bats in south-central Texas during the peak lactation period (15 June–15 July) to determine whether emergence behavior was associated with summer drought conditions and daily temperatures. Bats emerged significantly earlier during years with extreme drought conditions than during moist years. Bats emerged later on days with high surface temperatures in both dry and moist years, but there was no relationship between surface temperatures and timing of emergence in summers with normal moisture levels. We conclude that emergence behavior is a flexible animal response to climate and weather conditions and may be a useful indicator for monitoring animal response to long-term shifts in climate.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="language" language="en_US" qualifier="iso">en_US</dcvalue><dcvalue element="title" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Climate and Weather Impact Timing of Emergence of Bats</dcvalue><dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2012-08-02</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Winifred F. Frick</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Phillip M. Stepanian</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Jeffrey F. Kelly</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Kenneth W. Howard</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Charles M. Kuster</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Thomas H. Kunz</dcvalue><dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Phillip B. Chilson</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="none">We thank two anonymous reviewers for helpful comments on the manuscript and Barry Nickel for advice on statistical analysis. We thank the National Severe Storms Laboratory for radar data processing and access, in particular Brian Kaney and Katherine Willingham. We thank Danny Scipión and Sarah Stough for help with data preparation.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Conceived and designed the experiments: WFF THK JFK KWH PBC. Performed the experiments: WFF PMS PBC. Analyzed the data: WFF. Contributed reagents/materials/analysis tools: KWH CMK. Wrote the paper: WFF PMS JFK PBC.</dcvalue><dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none">PLOS ONE</dcvalue><dcvalue element="identifier" language="en_US" qualifier="citation"> Frick WF, Stepanian PM, Kelly JF, Howard KW, Kuster CM, et al. (2012) Climate and Weather Impact Timing of Emergence of Bats. PLoS ONE 7(8): e42737. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0042737</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">Attribution 3.0 United States</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="uri">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/us/</dcvalue><dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="requestable">false</dcvalue><dcvalue element="relation" qualifier="ispartofseries">PLoS ONE 7(8):e42737</dcvalue><dcvalue element="relation" qualifier="uri">http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0042737</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">PLOS</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Public Library of Science</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Open Access</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Open-Access</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Science</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Medicine</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Biology</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Research</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Peer-review</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Inclusive</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Interdisciplinary</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Ante-disciplinary</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Physics</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Chemistry</dcvalue><dcvalue element="subject" language="en_US" qualifier="none">Engineering</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="peerreview">Yes</dcvalue><dcvalue element="description" language="en_US" qualifier="peerreviewnotes">http://www.plosone.org/static/editorial#peer</dcvalue><dcvalue element="identifier" language="en_US" qualifier="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0042737</dcvalue></dublin_core>